Guide to the Anson Phelps Stokes Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Report of Rev. Anson Phelps Stokes on Education, Native Welfare and Race Relations in East and South Africa, Carnegie Corporation, New York, 1934.
"How We Can Create More Christian Attitudes and Practices in Race Relations in Washington" in Report of the Conference on the Betterment of Race Relations in Washington, D. C., February 12, 1935.
A Brief Biography of Booker Washington, Hampton Institute Press, 1936; enlarged from article in Dictionary of American Biography.
Doctor Dillard as a Bridge Builder: Remarks at the Complimentary Dinner to Dr. Dillard on his 80th Birthday, Charlottesville, Virginia, October 26, 1936.
"The Cultural Importance of Good Housing," April 18, 1936, a discussion before Conference on Better Housing among Negroes under auspices of Washington Committee on Housing, of which Dr. Stokes was Chairman.
Art and the Color Line, Printed for the consideration of the Executive Committee of the D.A.R. and for the Marian Anderson Committee, Washington, D.C., October, 1939.
"Negro Americans in Defense Industries" a statement of the Committee, of which he was Chairman, edited by Father La Farge and others, and published in the Congressional Record for Wednesday, May 7, 1941, by Hon. Thomas H. Eliot of Massachusetts.
Atlantic Charter and Africa from an American standpoint, Dr. Stokes as Chairman of the Committee on Africa, the War, and Peace Aims, wrote and edited the Introduction and most of the report, New York City, 1942; Revised Edition, 1943.
"Africa and Enduring Peace", summary of address at the Conference on African Affairs, Otterbein, June, 1942, in Christian Action in Africa, New York, 1942.
"Committee on the Negro American in Defense Industries" [a report of progress], Journal of Negro Education, Spring Number, 1944.
Phelps-Stokes Fund Policy, a mimeographed historical study in relation to Foundation trends and Negro needs, April, 1944.
Encyclopedia of the Negro - Preparatory Volume with Reference Lists and Reports, Introduction to report, prepared under the auspices of the Board of Directors of the Encyclopedia of the Negro of which Dr. Stokes was Chairman, New York, 1944; Revised Edition, New York, 1946.
"American Race Relations in War Time", Christian News Letter, London, December 27, 1944. Revised and enlarged for the Journal of Negro Education, Vol. XIV, No. 4. Fall of 1945.
Chapters XV on "The Church and Slavery" and XVII on "Problems of Adjustment in Fields of Racial and Religious Restriction" in forthcoming volumes on Church and State in the United States.
Treaty of Portsmouth (1905 September 5); African Americans -- Education; Civil rights; Clergy; Education; Indians of North America; Missionaries -- United States; Radicalism; Russo-Japanese War, 1904-1905; Socialism; World War, 1939-1945; China -- History -- Republic, 1912-1949; New Haven (Conn.) -- History; Soviet Union; United States -- Foreign relations; Abbott, Lyman, 1835-1922; Acheson, Dean, 1893-1971; Adams, James Luther, 1901-1994; Allen, George E. (George Edward), 1896-1973; Angell, James Rowland, 1869-1949; Asakawa, Kan'ichi, 1873-1948; Austin, Warren Robinson, 1877-1962; Baldwin, Simeon E. (Simeon Eben), 1840-1927; Beers, Clifford Whittingham, 1876-1943; Berle, Adolf A., Jr., 1895-1971; Bethune, Mary McLeod, 1875-1955; Beveridge, Albert J. (Albert Jeremiah), 1862-1927; Bingham, Hiram, 1875-1956; Bliss, Frederick Jones, 1859-1937; Bowman, Isaiah, 1878-1950; Brandegee, Frank B. (Frank Bosworth), 1864-1924; Bratenahl, George Carl Fitch, 1862-; Brawley, Benjamin, 1882-1939; Brewster, Chauncey B. (Chauncey Bunce), 1848-1941; Brooks, Philip Coolidge, 1906-1977; Brown, Elmer Ellsworth, 1861-1934; Buck, Pearl S. (Pearl Sydenstricker), 1892-1973; Buckley, William F., Jr., 1925-2008; Bullitt, William C. (William Christian), 1891-1967; Bunche, Ralph J. (Ralph Johnson), 1904-1971; Bundy, Harvey H.; Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1862-1947; Camp, Walter, 1859-1925; Canby, Henry Seidel, 1878-1961; Carter, Edward C. (Edward Clark), 1878-1954; Carver, George Washington, 1864?-1943; Churchill, Winston, 1871-1947; Clark, Charles Upson, 1875-1960; Coffin, Henry Sloane, 1877-1954; Commager, Henry Steele, 1902-1998; Cross, Wilbur L. (Wilbur Lucius), 1862-1948; Day, Clarence, 1874-1935; Day, Clive, 1871-1951; Day, George Parmly, 1876-1959; Delano, William Adams, 1874-1960; Depew, Chauncey M. (Chauncey Mitchell), 1834-1928; DeVries, William Levering, 1865-1937; Dillard, J. H. (James Hardy), 1856-1940; Drury, Samuel S. (Samuel Smith), 1878-1938; Du Bois, W. E. B. (William Edward Burghardt), 1868-1963; Dulles, John Foster, 1888-1959; Dwight, Timothy, 1828-1916; Eastman, George, 1854-1932; Eastman, Max, 1883-1969; Eliot, Charles William, 1834-1926; Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers), 1883-1950; Farman, Henry Walcott, 1853-1933; Farnam, William Whitman, 1844-1929; Farrand, Max, 1869-1945; Firestone, Harvey Samuel, 1868-1938; Fisher, Irving, 1867-1947; Flexner, Abraham, 1866-1959; Flint, Joseph Marshall, 1872-1944; Ford, Henry, 1863-1947; Fosdick, Raymond B. (Raymond Blaine), 1883-1972; Gerry, Peter Goelet, 1879-1957; Goodrich, Chauncey William, 1864-1956; Green, Theodore Francis, 1867-1966; Grenfell, Wilfred Thomason, Sir, 1865-1940; Grosvenor, Gilbert Hovey, 1875-1966; Hadley, Arthur Twining, 1856-1930; Harriman, W. Averell (William Averell), 1891-1986; Herskovits, Melville J. (Melville Jean), 1895-1963; Hillhouse, James, 1854-1938; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964; Hopkins, Archibald, 1842-1926; Hughes, Charles Evans, 1862-1948; Hull, Cordell, 1871-1955; Hume, Edward H. (Edward Hicks), 1876-1957; Hutchinson, C. Alan (Cecil Alan), 1914-; Huxley, Julian, 1887-1975; Jackson, Robert H., 1892-1954; Jameson, J. Franklin (John Franklin), 1859-1937; Johnson, Alvin Saunders, 1874-1971; Johnson, James Weldon, 1871-1938; Johnson, Joseph Travis, 1858-1919; Jones, Thomas Jesse, 1873-1950; Keller, Albert Galloway, 1874-1956; Kennan, George F. (George Frost), 1904-2005; Knollenberg, Bernhard, 1892-1973; Latourette, Kenneth Scott, 1884-1968; Lawrence, W. Appleton (William Appleton), 1889-1968; Leland, Waldo Gifford, 1879-1966; Lindbergh, Charles A. (Charles Augustus), 1902-1974; Lippmann, Walter, 1889-1974; Locke, Alain, 1885-1954; Lodge, Henry Cabot, Jr., 1902-1985; Lohman, Joseph D. (Joseph Dean), 1910-1968; Lohmann, Carl A. (Carl Albert), 1887-; Loram, C. T. (Charles Templeman), 1879-1940; Lovett, Sidney, 1890-1979; Lowell, A. Lawrence (Abbott Lawrence), 1856-1943; Luce, Henry Robinson, 1898-1967; MacCracken, H. N. (Henry Noble), 1880-; MacLeish, Archibald, 1892-1982; Malinowski, Bronislaw, 1884-1942; Malone, Dumas, 1892-1986; McCormick, Robert R. (Robert Rutherford), 1880-1955; McCormick, Vance Criswell, 1872-1946; Mellon, Andrew W. (Andrew William), 1855-1937; Mendell, Clarence W. (Clarence Whittlesey), 1883-1970; Meriam, Lewis, 1883-1972; Mills, Ogden Livingston, 1884-1937; Morgan, J. P. (John Pierpont), 1867-1943; Morgenthau, Henry, 1891-1967; Mott, John R. (John Raleigh), 1865-1955; Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949; Myrdal, Gunnar, 1898-1987; Nettleton, George Henry, 1874-1959; Newlands, Francis G. (Francis Griffith), 1848-1917; Niebuhr, Reinhold, 1892-1971; Osler, William, Sir, 1849-1919; Overman, Lee S. (Lee Slater), 1854-1930; Parsons, Edward Lambe, 1868-; Peabody, Endicott, 1857-1944; Peabody, George Foster, 1852-1938; Perkins, George C. (George Clement), 1839-1923; Pershing, John J. (John Joseph), 1860-1948; Phelps, William Lyon, 1865-1943; Pierson, George Wilson, 1904-1993; Putman, Herbert, 1861-; Reed, Edward Bliss, 1872-1940; Reid, Ogden Mills, 1882-1947; Reilly, Thomas L. (Thomas Lawrence), 1858-1924; Rhinelander, Philip Mercer, 1869-1939; Riley, James Whitcomb, 1849-1916; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison), 1839-1937; Rockefeller, John D., Jr. (John Davison), 1874-1960; Rockefeller, William Goodsell, 1870-1922; Rogers, James Gamble, 1867-1947; Rollins, Carl Purington, 1880-1960; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919; Root, Elihu, 1845-1937; Rose, Wycliffe, 1862-1931; Rosenwald, Julius, 1862-1932; Royce, Josiah, 1855-1916; Saltonstall, Leverett, 1892-1979; Seymour, Charles, 1885-1963; Seymour, George Dudley, 1859-1945; Sharp, William Graves, 1859-1922; Shaw, Gardiner Howland, 1893-1965; Sherrill, Charles Hitchcock, 1867-1936; Sizer, Theodore, 1892-1967; Small, John H. (John Humphrey), 1858-1946; Spargo, John, 1876-1966; Stimson, Henry L. (Henry Lewis), 1867-1950; Stokes, Anson Phelps, 1874-1958; Stokes, Rose Pastor, 1879-1933; Stone, Harlan Fiske, 1872-1946; Straight, Willard Dickerman, 1880-1918; Sumner, William Graham, 1840-1910; Taft, Charles Phelps, 1843-1929; Taft, Robert A. (Robert Alphonso), 1889-1953; Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930; Taylor, James Monroe, 1848-1916; Thomas, Norman, 1884-1968; Tolstoy, Alexandra, 1884-1979; Treadway, Allen Towner, 1867-1947; Twain, Mark, 1875-1960; Van Dusen, Henry P. (Henry Pitney), 1897-1975; Vanderbilt, Cornelius, 1843-1899; Vickrey, Charles Vernon, 1876-1966; Vincent, George E. (George Edgar), 1864-1941; Wadsworth, James Wolcott, 1877-1952; Wagner, Robert F. (Robert Ferdinand), 1877-1953; Walcott, Frederic Collin, 1869-1949; Warburg, Paul M. (Paul Moritz), 1868-1932; Washington, Booker T., 1856-1915; Weigle, Luther A. (Luther Allan), 1880-1976; Welch, Lewis Sheldon, 1867-1940; Wetmore, George Peabody, 1846-1921; Weyerhaeuser, Frederick King; White, Henry, 1850-1927; White, Walter, 1893-1955; White, William Allen, 1868-1944; Wickersham, George W. (George Woodward), 1858-1936; Williams, Aubrey Willis, 1890-1965; Williams, Frederick Wells, 1857-1928; Woodson, Carter Godwin, 1875-1950; Zook, George Frederick, 1885-1951; Stokes family; American Civil Liberties Union; Episcopal Church; Indian Rights Association; Phelps-Stokes Fund; Washington Cathedral; Yale University -- History; Yale University -- Officals and employees; Yale University -- Students; Yale-China Association
- Correspondence of Anson Phelps Stokes, 1879-(1892-1958); PART I. I; 57.5 linear feet (139 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Part I, Series I is divided into the "General Correspondence" and the "Family Correspondence" of Anson Phelps Stokes. Letters to and from Anson Phelps Stokes are filed together. Since Stokes retained carbon copies of most of his letters in his files, the full correspondence is represented.
  The 129 boxes of "General Correspondence" have been arranged into four chronological sub-sections: 1892-1921, 1922-1930 May 31, 1930 Jun 1 - 1939 Dec 31, 1940 Jan 1 - 1958 Aug 13.
  There is one folder of undated correspondence which appears at the end of the general correspondence.
  Within each chronological sub-section, correspondence is arranged alphabetically by the correspondent's last name. For the most part, correspondents are grouped together under general alphabetical headings, such as "An - Az, 1922-1923." The correspondence of some individuals has been placed in separate folders and filed at the end of the general folders. Thus, James Rowland Angell's correspondence with Stokes for the period from 1922 to 1930 May 31 appears after the general folders, "An - Az," for that period.
  To aid the researcher, a select list of correspondents has been prepared for each of the chronological sub-sections. Where applicable, the name of an organization or institution is given along with the correspondent's name. In most instances, Stokes filed letters under the name of the individual rather than the name of the organization or institution. These lists of correspondents appear in the register as Appendix I.
  Letters of congratulation or tribute relating to special events in the life of Anson Phelps Stokes are filed at the end of the appropriate chronological sub-section. The special events are:
  1) Engagement and wedding, 1903
  2) Resignation as Secretary of Yale University, 1921
  3) Resignation as Canon of Washington Cathedral, 1939
  4) Resignation as Chairman of the Board of Trustees of the Phelps-Stokes Fund, 1946
  5) Churchman of the Year Award, 1951
  6) Golden Wedding Anniversary, 1953
  7) Eightieth birthday, 1954
  Sympathy letters received by the Stokes family upon the death of Anson Phelps Stokes are filed at the end of the general correspondence.
  "Family Correspondence" consists of Anson Phelps Stokes's correspondence with Stokes family members and is arranged alphabetically by the family member's name. Each individual's correspondence with Anson Phelps Stokes is arranged chronologically. The family members have been limited to Stokes's wife and children, his parents, his paternal aunts and uncles and their families, and his eight brothers and sisters and their families. His wife's relatives remain in the general correspondence, as do a number of second and third cousins.
  Since many relatives and friends wrote to Anson and Carol Mitchell Phelps Stokes simultaneously, the bulk of her correspondence is filed with that of her husband. Letters of Carol Mitchell Phelps Stokes filed neither in the family nor the general correspondence of Anson Phelps Stokes have been filed in Part I, Series VI.
  Note: In certain instances, Stokes maintained a file of letters directly related to one of his publications. This correspondence is located with his writings in Part I, Series II. For example, letters from friends and colleagues commenting on "The Two Fronts of Freedom" are filed with a printed copy of the speech in Part I, Series II, under "Articles, Addresses, and Public Statements." Similarly, Stokes's file of research correspondence for Church and State in the United States is with the manuscript of the book in Part I, Series II.
  Note: Correspondence of the Phelps Stokes family which is neither to nor from Anson Phelps Stokes has not been included in Part I, Series I. It is filed in Part I, Series VI.
  - General Correspondence, 1892-1921
    - A, 1892-1921 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - B, 1892-1921, undated (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
    - Ca-Ch, 1892-1921 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Ci-Cz, 1892-1920 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Ci-Cz, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Clemens, Samuel Langhorne, 1901 November 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      General note
      Letters To APS/From APS: 1
    - Cleveland, Grover, 1892 December 8; 1900 October 23 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 2
    - Cunliffe, J.W., 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 10
    - D, 1892-1921 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
    - E, 1892-1921 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - F, 1892-1921, n. d. (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
    - First National Bank of New Haven, 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - G, 1892-1921 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - H, 1892-1921 (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
    - Hadley, Arthur Twining, 1899-1905 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 16/1
    - Hadley, Arthur Twining, 1906-1918 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 24/4
    - Hadley, Arthur Twining, 1920-1921 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 7/3
    - I-J, 1892-1921 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - K, 1892-1921 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - L, 1892-1921 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Ma-Mc, 1892-1921 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - McCulloch, James W., Phelps-Stokes Estates, 1920-1921 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 43
    - Me-Mi, 1920-1921 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Mitchell, Anna V.S., 1921 February 2 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Mitchell, Clarence Blair, 1920-1921 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 4
    - Mitchell, Sarah L., 1903 October 12 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Mj-Mz, 1892-1921 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Na-Ne, 1892-1921 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Nd-Nz, 1892-1921 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - O, 1892-1921 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - P, 1892-1920 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - P, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Q-R, 1892-1921 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1896 March 30; 1896 April 2; 1896 April 21 (Box 3, Folder 38)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 3
    - Sa-Se, 1892-1921 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Sakai, Barnabas T., Circa1896-1897, 1899 July 7 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Sf-Sr, 1892-1921 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - St-Sz, 1892-1921 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - T, 1892-1921 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Taft, William Howard, 1906 October 23; 1909 February 22; 1909 November 21; 1910 January 10; 1910 March 9 (Box 3, Folder 44)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 5
    - U-V, 1892-1921 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Vickrey, Charles V., 1921 January-April (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Vickrey, Charles V., 1921 May-June (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Wa-Wd, 1892-1921 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - We-Wg, 1892-1921 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Wh-Wz, 1892-1921 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - X-Y-Z, 1892-1921 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Letters Requesting Financial Aid, 1900-1901 (unless otherwise indicated)
      - A (Box 4, Folder 52)
      - B (Box 4, Folder 53-54)
      - C (Box 4, Folder 55)
      - D (Box 4, Folder 56)
      - E (Box 4, Folder 57)
      - F (Box 4, Folder 58)
      - G (Box 4, Folder 59)
      - H (Box 5, Folder 60)
      - I (Box 5, Folder 61)
      - J (Box 5, Folder 62)
      - K (Box 5, Folder 63)
      - L (Box 5, Folder 64)
      - M (Box 5, Folder 65)
      - N (Box 5, Folder 66)
      - O (Box 5, Folder 67)
      - P (Box 5, Folder 68)
      - Q (Box 5, Folder 69)
      - R (Box 5, Folder 70)
      - S (Box 5, Folder 71)
      - S (Box 6, Folder 72)
      - T (Box 6, Folder 73)
      - U (Box 6, Folder 74)
      - V (Box 6, Folder 75)
      - W (Box 6, Folder 76)
      - X-Y (Box 6, Folder 77)
      - Z (Box 6, Folder 78)
      - Unidentified, undated (Box 6, Folder 79)
      - Fragments, undated (Box 6, Folder 80)
    - Congratulatory Letters on Engagement and Wedding, 1903-1904 (unless otherwise indicated)
      - A (Box 6, Folder 81)
      - B (Box 6, Folder 82)
      - C (Box 6, Folder 83)
      - D (Box 6, Folder 84)
      - E-F-G (Box 6, Folder 85)
      - H (Box 7, Folder 86)
      - I-J-K (Box 7, Folder 87)
      - L (Box 7, Folder 88-89)
      - M (Box 7, Folder 90-91)
      - N-O (Box 7, Folder 92)
      - P (Box 7, Folder 93)
      - Q-R (Box 7, Folder 94)
      - S (Box 7, Folder 95-96)
      - T (Box 7, Folder 97)
      - U-Z (Box 7, Folder 98)
      - Unidentified, 1903-1904, n. d. (Box 7, Folder 99)
    - Letters re: Yale Memorabilia
      - Letters from M.B. Brainard, Max Farrand, Lydia F. Spofford, and Sarah C.D. Woodward, 1908-1915 (Box 7, Folder 100)
        Letters To APS/From APS: 11
    - Letters re: Resignation as Secretary of Yale University
      - Copy of Anson Phelps Stokes's letter of resignation, 1921 February 7 (Box 8, Folder 101)
      - Letters to APS sent in 1921 re: resignation
      - A (Box 8, Folder 102)
      - B (Box 8, Folder 103)
      - C (Box 8, Folder 104)
      - D (Box 8, Folder 105)
      - E (Box 8, Folder 106)
      - F (Box 8, Folder 107)
      - G (Box 8, Folder 108)
      - H (Box 8, Folder 109)
      - I-J (Box 8, Folder 110)
      - K (Box 8, Folder 111)
      - L (Box 8, Folder 112)
      - M (Box 8, Folder 113)
      - N-O (Box 8, Folder 114)
      - P-Q (Box 8, Folder 115)
      - R (Box 8, Folder 116)
      - S (Box 8, Folder 117)
      - T (Box 8, Folder 118)
      - U-V (Box 8, Folder 119)
      - W-Z (Box 8, Folder 120)
  - General Correspondence, 1922-1930 May 31
    - Aa-Am, 1922-1930 May 31 (Box 9, Folder 121-131)
    - Alexander, Will W., 1922 June 2 - 1930 May 23 (Box 9, Folder 131A)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 25/37
    - American University Union and the American Council on Education
      See: Part I, box 176, folders 21-48
    - An-Az, 1922-1927 July 15 (Box 9, Folder 132-135)
    - An-Az, 1927 July 16 - 1930 May 31 (Box 10, Folder 136-138)
    - Angell, James Rowland, 1924 January 1 - 1925 December 31 (Box 10, Folder 139)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 10/9
    - Angell, James Rowland, 1926 January 1 - 1928 December 31 (Box 10, Folder 140)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 21/18
    - Angell, James Rowland, 1929 January 1 - 1930 May 31 (Box 10, Folder 141)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 16/20
    - Austin, Chellis A., 1922-1925 December 31 (Box 10, Folder 142)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 19/15
    - Austin, Chellis A., 1926 January 1 - 1930 May 31 (Box 10, Folder 143)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 15/12
    - Ba-Bd, 1922-1930 May 31 (Box 10, Folder 144-149)
    - Be-Bh, 1922-1930 May 31 (Box 11, Folder 150-155)
    - Behringer, Emma P., Phelps-Stokes Estates, 1922-1930 May 31 (Box 11, Folder 156)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 17/14
    - Berry, Gordon L., 1929 November 1 - 1930 May 31 (Box 11, Folder 157)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 20/18
    - Bevis, Palmer, 1922-1924 December 31 (Box 11, Folder 158)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 27/23
    - Bevis, Palmer, 1925 January 1 - May 31 (Box 11, Folder 159)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 27/21
    - Bevis, Palmer, 1925 June 1 - September 30 (Box 11, Folder 160)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 21/13
    - Bevis, Palmer, 1925 October 1 - 1926 March 15 (Box 11, Folder 161)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 19/12
    - Bevis, Palmer, 1926 March 16 - June 30 (Box 11, Folder 162)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 26/20
    - Bevis, Palmer, 1926 July 1 - October 31 (Box 11, Folder 163)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 20/12
    - Bevis, Palmer, 1926 November 1 - December 31 (Box 11, Folder 164)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 22/20
    - Bevis, Palmer, 1927 January 1 - February 28 (Box 11, Folder 165)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 21/8
    - Bevis, Palmer, 1927 March 1 - April 30 (Box 12, Folder 166)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 24/22
    - Bevis, Palmer, 1927 May 1 - August 31 (Box 12, Folder 167)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 17/19
    - Bevis, Palmer, 1927 September 1 - 1928 May 31 (Box 12, Folder 168)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 28/32
    - Bevis, Palmer, 1928 June 1 - December 31 (Box 12, Folder 169)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 21/17
    - Bevis, Palmer, 1929 January 1 - December 31 (Box 12, Folder 170)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 23/34
    - Bevis, Palmer, 1930 January 1 - May 31 (Box 12, Folder 171)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 18/23
    - Bi-Bn, 1922-1930 May 31 (Box 12, Folder 172-177)
    - Bingham, Dr. Arthur W., 1922 May - 1924 May (Box 12, Folder 178)
    - Bo-Bq, 1922-1930 May 31 (Box 13, Folder 179-184)
    - Br-Bt, 1922-1928 December 31 (Box 13, Folder 185-191)
    - Bra-Bre, 1929 January 1 - 1930 May 31 (Box 13, Folder 192-193)
    - Bri-Bt, 1929 January 1 - 1930 May 31 (Box 13, Folder 194)
    - Bratenahl, The Very Rev. G.C.F., 1922-1925 December 31 (Box 14, Folder 195)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 19/31
    - Bratenahl, The Very Rev. G.C.F., 1926 January 1 - 1927 July 15 (Box 14, Folder 196)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 25/40
    - Bratenahl, The Very Rev. G.C.F., 1927 July 16 - 1928 December 31 (Box 14, Folder 197)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 20/37
    - Bratenahl, The Very Rev. G.C.F., 1929 January 1 - 1930 May 31 (Box 14, Folder 198)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 17/34
    - Bratenahl, The Very Rev. G.C.F.
      See: Part I, box 184, folder 228-236
    - Breen, Margaret J.
      See: James W. McCulloch, Part I, box 2, folder 26
    - Brierley, W.W., 1922-1926 December 31 (Box 14, Folder 199)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 29/20
    - Brierley, W.W., 1927 January 1 - 1930 May 31 (Box 14, Folder 200)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 19/18
    - Brookings, Robert S., 1922-1930 May 31 (Box 14, Folder 201)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 5/13
    - Brown, Harry W. Jr., 1927 June - Jul; 1929 January - December (Box 14, Folder 202)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 10/35
    - Brown, Harry W. Jr., 1930 January 1 - May 31 (Box 14, Folder 203)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 12/15
    - Brown, Harry W. Jr.
      See: Part I, box 184, folder 228-238
    - Brown, Helen Gilman (Mrs. William Adams Brown), 1929 June 1 - 1930 May 31 (Box 14, Folder 204)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 1/6
    - Brown, John Crosby, 1923-1924, 1926, 1930 (Box 14, Folder 205)
      Letters To APS/From APS: 18/10